<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.nsp13182">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">The Indians</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<sponsor>This project is supported in part by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Geraldine W. &amp; Robert J. Dellenback Foundation.</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.nsp13182</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="a" type="main">The Indians</title>
<title level="a" type="sub">Complaints from the Cut-off Bands - They Desire to be Treated Like Other Tribes</title>
<title level="j">New York Times</title>
<pubPlace>New York (N.Y.)</pubPlace>
<date when="1872-04-25">April 25, 1872</date>
</bibl>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article">

<pb facs="wfc.nsp13182.001"/>

<p>A report to the War Department from Col. J.J. REYNOLDS, commanding the Third Cavalry, dated Fort McPherson, Nebraska, 9th inst., announces a visit to the post by the Indian chief WHISTLER, who desired to have it stated for the information of the President that the "Cut-off" bands of Indians had not received that consideration at the hands of the Great Father that had been accorded to the other tribes of Sioux and to the Spotted Tail bands. The cut-off bands of Ogallalla Sioux Indians, according to Col. REYNOLDS' information, consist of three bands headed respectively by BLACK BEAR, PAWNEE KILLER and WHISTLER. The two former bands have gone to the reservation at White Clay, but WHISTLER declares contrary to their wishes, and that they will not remain there contentedly under present arrangements. WHISTLER is now south of the Platte, about 100 miles west of Fort McPherson, and has asked for permission to hunt in that neighborhood until an answer can be received in regard to this communication. His band has been where they now are for nearly two years, and have committed no depredations. They prefer to remain south of the Platte. Col. REYNOLDS assured him there was not the least probability that this request would be granted. WHISTLER declares his willingness to conform to any decision, but strongly insists that the Cut-offs shall be put together and have an agent. This last request, he desired to have said, was the most important of all to the Cut-off bands, and he hoped the request would receive due consideration, and that an answer might be promptly sent to him. WHISTLER further states that ever since the council at Fort Laramie in 1868 the Cut-off bands have been dissatisfied, and have not well understood their status. This state of affairs, according to him can be remedied only by granting the above request. Lieut. Gen. SHERIDAN says in forwarding this communication: "WHISTLER is a very good Indian, but PAWNEE KILLER is not and never has been. I think it would be unwise to let these bands remain south of the Platte. The Republican Valley is now settling up so rapidly, that I fear a collision may take place if these Indians are allowed to remain there." Col. REYNOLDS further states that on 30th March, SPOTTED TAIL and his band were en route for Big Springs, from whence, after receiving ponies and rations, the band left on 4th instant for White Clay reservation.</p>


</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
