<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.loc.gov/standards/vracore/vra-strict.xsd"?>

<vra xmlns="http://www.vraweb.org/vracore4.htm">

<work id="wfc.img.pht00090">
<agentSet>
<display></display>
<agent>
<name></name>
<dates></dates>
<role></role>
</agent>
</agentSet> 
<dateSet>
<display></display>
<date></date>
</dateSet>
<descriptionSet>
<description>By 1935 Lakotas involved in shows dressed specifically for performance. When the Little Elks posed for this souvenir postcard, they wore clothing influenced by tradition but much more extravagant. The reverse side of the souvenir postcard has the family members' names handwritten on it and a postmark showing that it was sent from a postal station at the Brussels exposition. </description>
</descriptionSet>
<inscriptionSet>
<inscription>
<text>Souvenir of the American Indian Villages Real Sioux Indians from pine ridge So. Dakotah U S Government reservations. They are in Europe with Clarance Shultz well known cowboy from Marland. Okla U S. A. Souvenir de l'Exposition de Bruxelles 1936 Veritables Sioux Peaux-Rouges venant des reserves nationales du gouvernement americain a Pine Ridge So. Dakotah. Souvenir Tentoonstelling Brussel 1935 Echte Sioux Roodhuiden komend van de Amerikaansche regeering resives in Pine Ridge Zuid Dakotah. Nels. Bruxelles Brussel Ville Lilliput Stad Repr. strict. int. John Little Elk Lucy Little Elk Virgie Little Elk Monsieur Albert Geuse Charmane Geuse Binche</text>
</inscription>
</inscriptionSet>
<locationSet>
<location>
<name></name>
</location>
</locationSet>
<relationSet>
<relation>Friesen, Steve. Lakota Performers in Europe: Their Culture and the Artifacts They Left Behind. University of Oklahoma Press, 2017.</relation>
<relation>http://www.codystudies.org/friesen/</relation>
<relation>wfc.img.pht00071</relation>
</relationSet>
<rightsSet>
<rights>
<rightsHolder>Fran&#231;ois Chladiuk Collection</rightsHolder>
<text></text>
</rights>
</rightsSet>
<sourceSet>
<display></display>
<source>
<name type="electronic"></name>
</source>
</sourceSet>
<subjectSet>
<display>Lakota Performers</display>
<subject>
<term>American Indians</term>
<term type="personalName">Little Elks, John</term>
<term type="personalName">Little Elks, Virginia</term>
<term type="personalName">Little Elks, Lucy</term>
<term type="personalName">Hermans, August</term>
<term></term>
<term></term>
</subject>
</subjectSet>
<techniqueSet>
<technique></technique>
</techniqueSet>   
<titleSet>
<title>John Little Elks, Virginia Little Elks, and Lucy Little Elks (postcard verso)</title>
</titleSet>
<worktypeSet>
<worktype>postcard</worktype>
</worktypeSet>
<image>
<agentSet>
<agent>
<name type="personal"></name>
<role></role>
</agent>
</agentSet>
<dateSet>
<date></date>
</dateSet>
<relationSet>
<relation/>
</relationSet>
<rightsSet>
<rights>
<rightsHolder>Fran&#231;ois Chladiuk Collection</rightsHolder>
<text></text>
</rights> 
</rightsSet>
<worktypeSet>
<worktype>digital image</worktype>
</worktypeSet>
</image>
</work> 

</vra>