<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.scr00007.044">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main" xml:lang="en">The Queen in London</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>Encoding by</resp>
<name>Lily Jensen</name>
<name>Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2025</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.scr00007.044</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="a" type="main" xml:lang="en">The Queen in London</title>
<title level="a" type="sub" xml:lang="en">Visit to Westminster and the American Exhibition</title>
<title level="j">Daily Telegraph</title>
<title level="m">Annie Oakley: marbled paper scrapbook</title>
<date when="1887-05-12">May 12, 1887</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>McCracken Research Library, Buffalo Bill Center of the West</repository>
<idno>MS6.3681</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>



<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term>Annie Oakley</term>
<term>Buffalo Bill's Wild West in Britain</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>Wild West Shows</term>
<term>Exhibitions</term>
<term>Shooting</term>
<term>Horsemanship</term>
<term>Horses</term>
<term>Trick Riding</term>
<term>American Indians</term>
<term>Mexicans</term>
<term>Cowboys</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Oakley, Annie, 1860-1926</term>
<term>Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901</term>
<term>Bradley, George Granville, 1821-1903</term>
<term>Wilbraham, Edward Bootle, 1771-1853</term>
<term>Stanley, Arthur Penrhyn, 1815-1881</term>
<term>Gower, Ronald Sutherland, Lord, 1845-1916</term>
<term>Hughes-Hallett, Francis 1838-1903</term>
<term>Speed, John Gilmer, 1853-1909</term>
<term>Beatrice, Princess Henry of Battenberg, 1857-1944</term>
<term>Henry Maurice, Prince of Battenberg, 1858-1896</term>
<term>Ponsonby, Henry Frederick, Sir, 1825-1895</term>
<term>Russell, Henry Sturgis</term>
<term>Applin, Vincent Augustin</term>
<term>Taylor, William Levi, 1857-1924</term>
<term>Irving, Bennie; Smith, Lillian Frances, 1871-1930</term>
<term>Salsbury, Nathan, 1846-1902</term>
<term>Red Shirt, 1845?-1925</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>London (England)</term>
<term>Earl's Court (London, England)</term>
<term>Kensington (London, England)</term>
<term>Brompton (London, England)</term>
<term>Olympia (London, England</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>


</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lj">Jensen, Lily </name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article" xml:lang="en">

<pb facs="wfc.scr00007.044"/>

<head>Daily Telegraph</head>

<head>THE QUEEN IN LONDON.</head>

<head>VISIT TO WESTMINSTER AND THE AMERICAN EXHIBITION.</head>

<ab>LONDON, THURSDAY, MAY 12, 1887</ab>

<p>Her Majesty's visit to London yesterday was partly official and partly for a novel form of afternoon's amusement and relaxation from State duties. Shortly after eleven the Queen drove from Buckingham Palace to Westminster Abbey, where she was received by Dean Bradley and the Abbey officials, and inspected the various preparations being made for the Jubilee service to take place on June 21. The Dean, the Lord Chamberlain (Lord Lathom), to whose department the arrangements officially belong, Mr. Plunket, and Sir H. Ponsonby Fane conducted the Queen over the Abbey, and explained all details. Her Majesty made a few suggestions, and, having expressed her pleasure with the proposed plan of the ceremony, drove back to the Palace. Before leaving the Queen paid a visit to the grave of Dean Stanley. In the afternoon the Royal party left the Palace, and drove through Earl's-court and West Kensington to see "Buffalo Bill."</p>

<p>Truly Colonel W. F. Cody should feel honoured, for in the last week all the notabilities of London,—princes, politicians, and players—have visited what can now be fairly called "Wild West Brompton." Yesterday came his crowning triumph, for it was her Majesty's Royal will and pleasure to witness the performance of the picturesque people who are already the talk of the town. As in the case of the Queen's visit to Olympia, the entertainment was of a strictly private nature, the public being admitted to the Exhibition, but not to the amphitheatre. The Royal carriage came into the arena about half-past five, and with a suggestion of Ascot formality drove round the circle to the centre of the amphitheatre, where a crimson velvet daïs, decorated with orchids, had been prepared for her Majesty's use. The Queen, who looked in remarkably good spirits, was received by the Marquis of Lorne and the representatives of the Executive Council, comprising Lord Ronald Gower, Colonel Hughes-Hallett, M. P., Mr. John Priestman, Mr. Wm. Lee Thornton, Mr. J. G. Speed, and Colonel Griffin. With her Majesty came the Princess Beatrice and Prince Henry of Battenberg, and the Royal party was attended by the Duchess of Athole and Sir Henry and Lady Ponsonby, with Colonel Gardiner and Sir Henry Ewart as equerries. The Marquis of Lorne having duly presented the president, Colonel Henry Russell, the director, Mr. Whibley, and the secretary of the Exhibition, Mr. Vincent Applin, a selection from the performance was given. The "orator" was not called on to exercise his excellent powers of sonorous elocution from the rostrum, but stood just outside on the left of the Royal box and performed his duties of introducing the various groups. Mexican Vaqueros, Indians, cowboys, "a group of American girls," as the "orator" put it, and, in short, the whole show was paraded before her Majesty, the Indians sweeping past at full gallop with wild cries of delight. To a man every one of them knew the real meaning of the tiny audience and the honour of the occasion, and so they put their hearts into their work, and fought, plunged, danced, and shouted with rare spirit. "Buck Taylor'' dashed up and saluted; the little "cowboy," Master Bennie Irving, kissed his small hands in token of his respect, and when, finally, Buffalo Bill had reined up his white mustang, waved his salutations, and dismissed his little army, the selected programme was gone through. A three-quarter mile race between a "Cow-boy," Indian, and Mexican, was followed by the "pony express," with its incident of a quick remount, then Miss Lilian Smith showed her skill with the rifle, and after her performance was called to the Royal box and complimented. Then little Miss Annie Oakley showed what she could do with clay pigeons, and in her turn was presented and complimented, and made the prettiest of curtseys before she scampered off.</p>

<p>Next came the picking up of handkerchiefs at full gallop by "Buck Taylor," the gigantic, and buck-jumping on the snorting mule "Suicide," which animal in its over loyal zeal seemed at one moment apparently desirous of paying its personal respects to Royalty till duly "warned off" by the "orator" and Mr. Salisbury. Then followed the "war dance," wherein the painted Indians crowded as close as they could to the Royal box, and placed themselves ambitiously in evidence. What the whoopings and yells quite meant we have no means of judging; but anyhow they were a very sincere form of enthusiasm of some sort. After Sergeant Bates had waved his flag to the strains of "Yankee Doodle," Miss Mina Hickock had done her haute école business, and Buffalo Bill had shown his shooting powers on horseback, the "Deadwood coach" scene, with Indian attack and "cowboy" defence, was spiritedly enacted. Lord Ronald Gower and Colonel Hughes Hallett, as on the opening day, took their places inside as passengers; and we are bound to say the noble lord and the hon. member for Rochester comported themselves with much dignity under a seemingly murderous fire. The performance wound up with the dramatic attack on the isolated hut on the imaginary rancho, in the course of which many "braves'' of the Araphoes, Brule Sioux, Shoshones, and Ogalallas temporarily "strewed the ground." When all the shooting was over and the "braves'' had recovered and run home to the rocky fastnesses of the distant panorama, Colonel Cody was presented to her Majesty, who graciously expressed her delight with the show, regretted she had not more time to spare, and trusted to be able to come again. Mr. Nate Salisbury, the manager, having been presented, her Majesty sent for Ogila-sa, better known as "Red Shirt," the Chief of the Sioux. That redoubtable warrior advanced, in all the glories of his full-feathered war-bonnet, made a grave bow, and stood as still as a statue in the presence of what was to him "the Great White Queen." The few kind words of congratulation were interpreted to him, and he returned brief thanks with smiles. After a pause he desired the interpreter to say that "he had come a long way to see her Majesty, and was glad," after which "Red Shirt," feeling the interview was over, strode abruptly away. His notions of Court etiquette are primitive, but for all that there was both dignity and respect in his manner.</p>

</div1>
</body>

<back>
</back>
</text>
</TEI>
