<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.scr00007.121">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main" xml:lang="en">Buffalo Bill’s Wild West - Miss Annie Oakley, the most Famous Girl-Shot in the World</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>Encoding by</resp>
<name>Lily Jensen</name>
<name>Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2025</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.scr00007.121</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="a" type="main" xml:lang="en">Buffalo Bill’s Wild West - Miss Annie Oakley, the most Famous Girl-Shot in the World</title>
<title level="j"></title>
<title level="m">Annie Oakley: marbled paper scrapbook</title>
<date when="1887">1887-1892</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>McCracken Research Library, Buffalo Bill Center of the West</repository>
<idno>MS6.3681</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>



<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term>Annie Oakley</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>Shooting</term>
<term>Shooting contests</term>
<term>Rifles</term>
<term>Sharpshooters</term>
<term>Medals</term>
<term>Firearms</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Oakley, Annie, 1860-1926</term>
<term>Edward VII King of Great Britain, 1841-1910</term>
<term>Sitting Bull, 1831-1890</term>
<term>Bogardus, Adam H.</term>
<term>Carver, William F. (William Frank), 1840-1927</term>
<term>Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>London (England)</term>
<term>Darke County (Ohio)</term>
<term>New York (N.Y.)</term>
<term>Saint Paul (Minn.)</term>
<term>Cincinnati (Ohio)</term>
<term>Canada</term>
<term>Michigan</term>
<term>Kansas</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>


</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lj">Jensen, Lily </name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article" xml:lang="en">

<pb facs="wfc.scr00007.121"/>

<head>BUFFALO BILL'S WILD WEST.</head>

<head>Miss Annie Oakley, the most Famous
Girl-Shot in the World.</head>

<ab>(See Illustration, page 16.)</ab>

<p>This celebrated shot was born at Woodland, Darke Co., Ohio, August 13, 1866. Ever since a child she has had an inherent love for firearms and hunting, and at the age of 10 she, as often as ammunition was obtainable, would smuggle her brother's musket and steal into the woods, where game at that time was plentiful. Naturally she was a good shot, and came home well supplied with game. At the age of 12 she was presented with a 14-gauge muzzle-loading shot-gun. With this she improved rapidly and became such a fine shot that she rarely missed quail or pheasant; and at the age of 14 she has paid off a mortgage on her father's homestead with money earned from the sale of game and skins, shot and trapped by herself alone. Then came a local reputation, and with improved firearms she attracted wider notice. For the past five years she has been shooting before the public with great success; though, like the modest little girl she is, she never laid claim to being a champion, yet in 1883-4 Richard K. Fox, of New York, had so much confidence in her ability that he offered to back her against any other so-called champion. <persName xml:id="sitting.bull">Sitting Bull</persName>, the great Indian chief, after seeing her shoot in St. Paul, Minn., adopted her in the Sioux tribe, giving her the name of "Watanya Cicilia," or Little Sure Shot.</p>

<p>The first two years before the public she devoted to rifle and pistol shooting, and there is very little in that line she has not accomplished. At Tiffin, Ohio, she once shot a 10-cent piece held between the thumb and forefinger of an attendant, at a distance of 30 feet. In April, 1884, she attempted to beat the best record made at balls thrown in the air, using a 22 cal. rifle. The best record was 979, made by Dr. Ruth. <persName xml:id="oakley.a">Miss Oakley</persName> used a Stevens 22 cal. rifle, and broke 943. Her first attempt at clay pigeon and trap shooting was made about three years ago in Cincinnati, shooting with such fine shots as Bandle, McMurchy, and other noted shots.</p>

<p>In February, 1885, she attempted the feat of shooting at 5,000 balls in one day, loading the guns herself. In this feat she used three 16-gauge hammer guns. The balls were thrown straight away from three traps, 15 yards rise. Out of the 5,000 shot at, she broke 4,772. On the second thousand she only missed 16, making the best 1,000-ball record—984. This feat was accomplished near Cincinnati, Ohio, in less than nine hours.</p>

<p>Besides the thousands of exhibitions she has given, she has shot in 31 matches and tournaments, winning 25 prizes. Her collection of medals and firearms, all of which have been won or presented to her is considered the finest in America.</p>

<p>She has hunted in many of the game sections of America and Canada, and says, with a pardonable pride, that she has shot quail in Virginia, ducks in Illinois, prairie chickens in Kansas, and deer in Northern Michigan. Her style and position at the trap is considered perfection by such critics as Budd, Stice, Erb, <persName xml:id="bogardus.a">Bogardus</persName>, Cody, <persName xml:id="carver.w">Carver</persName>, and the English champions, Graham and Price. Shooting clay pigeons, she has a record of 96 out of 100. At live pigeons her best record is 23 out of 25, made in a match for 100 dollars.</p>

<p>What makes Miss Oakley's feats more surprising is the fact that she is small in stature and weighs only 110 pounds.</p>

<p>Besides her wonderful marksmanship, Miss Oakley is an accomplished housekeeper, as the neat and cheery appearance of her tent on Arapeah Avenue, withing the encampment, testifies, and those visitors who are fortunate to be invited within cannot but admire the quiet and ladylike manner in which she acts the part of hostess. The <persName xml:id="albert.edward">Prince of Wales</persName> was particularly pleased with her, and complimented her most highly, as did also the <persName xml:id="victoria.q">Queen</persName>.</p>


</div1>
</body>

<back>
</back>
</text>
</TEI>
