<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.nsp13195">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Untitled [Under Frankey's guidance, I made my way]</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<sponsor>This project is supported in part by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Geraldine W. &amp; Robert J. Dellenback Foundation.</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.nsp13195</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note>Date may be 1887 or 1888.</note>
<note>Newspaper article is incomplete and truncated; composed of cropped portions.</note>
</notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="a" type="main">Untitled [Under Frankey's guidance, I made my way]</title>
<title level="j">London Evening News</title>
<pubPlace>London, England</pubPlace>
<date when="1887-04-19">April 19, [1887]</date>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Buffalo Bill Center of the West; MS6, William F. Cody collection</repository>
<idno>MS6.3681.003.07 (Oakley scrapbook)</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term>Wild West in England</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>Firearms</term>
<term>Interviews</term>
<term>Muzzle-loading firearms</term>
<term>Rifles</term>
<term>Sharpshooters</term>
<term>Shooting contests</term>
<term>Shotguns</term>
<term>Targets (Shooting)</term>
<term>Traveling exhibitions</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Oakley, Annie, 1860-1926</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
<change when="2018"><name xml:id="lc">Clark, L.</name> <name xml:id="sh"> Hanna, Sam</name> <name xml:id="ak">Kinnen, Anna </name> <name xml:id="br">Roberts, Briana</name> Proofreading</change>
<change when="2018"><name>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Crowdsourcing (transcribe.unl.edu)</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article">

<pb facs="wfc.nsp13195.001"/>


<note>London Evening News</note>
<note>April 19th</note> 

<p>Under Frankey's guidance, I made my way through further rows of neat tents, until we arrived at that inhabited by Miss<persName> Annie Oakley</persName>, the champion lady shot of America. This young lady is possessed of a decidedly pretty and winsome face, of sweet and gentle manners, and a soft, girlish voice. Having been formerly introduced, Miss Oakley proceeded to give me a few particulars of her life and adventures.</p>

<ab>AN AMAZONIAN RIFLE SHOOTER.</ab>

<p>"I am about twenty years of age," said this young Amazon, "and have been fond of shooting from the time I was a toddling mite. At the age of twelve I was presented with a fourteen-guage muzzle-loading shot-gun. With this I practised all day long, and became so good a shot that by the time I had reached the age of fourteen I had paid off a mortgage on my father's homestead with money earned from the sale of game and skins, shot and trapped entirely by myself. Once at a place called Tiffin, in Ohio, I shot a ten-cent. piece, held between the thumb and forefinger of an attendant, at a distance of 30 feet. In 1884 I attempted to beat the best record made at balls thrown in the air, using a 22-cal. rifle. The best record was 979, made by Dr. Ruth. I used a Stevens 22-cal. rifle, and broke 944. A few months after this I attempted the feat of shooting at 5,000 balls in one day, loading the guns myself. I used three 16-guage hammer guns. The balls were thrown straight away from the three traps, fifteen yards rise. Out of the 5,000 shot at I broke 4,772. On the second thousand I only missed 16, making the best 1,000 ball record&#8212;984. I took nine hours to do the whole thing. I have shot in many thousands of exhibitions, in thirty-one matches and tournaments, and have won twenty-five prizes. In shooting clay pigeons I have recorded ninety-six out of one hundred, in live pigeons twenty-three out of twenty-five, and I have received congratulations from Budd, Stice, Erb, <persName xml:id="bogardus.a">Bogardus</persName>, Cody, <persName xml:id="carver.w">Carver</persName>, and the English champions, Graham and Price."</p>

<p>Miss Oakley having kindly showed me her numerous costly medals, of which she possesses quite a magnificent collection, and having assured me that she does not claim any championship, but looks upon her skill merely as a matter of dollars and cents, Frankey White bore me off to other <gap reason="missing"/> camp. <hi rend="italic">En route</hi> for the stables <gap reason="truncated"/></p>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
