<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.mem00014">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Story of the Wild West and Camp-Fire Chats</title>
<author>Cody, William F. (William Frederick), 1846-1917</author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<sponsor>This project is supported in part by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Geraldine W. &amp; Robert J. Dellenback Foundation.</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.mem00014</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>Cody, William F. (William Frederick), 1846-1917</author>
<title level="m" type="main">Story of the Wild West and Camp-Fire Chats</title>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1888">1888</date>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Buffalo Bill Center of the West; MS327, Wojtowicz collection</repository>
<idno>MS327.OS1.16</idno>
</msIdentifier>
<msContents>
<p></p>
</msContents>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Memorabilia</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Programs</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>Adventure stories, American</term>
<term>Advertising</term>
<term>American frontier</term>
<term>American Indians</term>
<term>Books</term>
<term>Drawings and graphics</term>
<term>Frontier and pioneer life</term>
<term>Historical Publishing Company</term>
<term>Historical reenactments</term>
<term>Indians of North America</term>
<term>Kings, queens, rulers, etc</term>
<term>Little Bighorn, Battle of the, Mont., 1876</term>
<term>Melodrama, American</term>
<term>Promotions</term>
<term>West (U.S.) History</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Alexandra, Queen, consort of Edward VII, King of Great Britain, 1844-1925</term>
<term>Boone, Daniel, 1734-1820</term>
<term>Carson, Kit, 1809-1868</term>
<term>Crockett, Davy, 1786-1836</term>
<term>Crook, George, 1829-1890</term>
<term>Custer, George A. (George Armstrong), 1839-1876</term>
<term>Edward VII, King of Great Britain, 1841-1910</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2018"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
<change when="2018"><name xml:id="ak">Kinnen, Anna</name> <name xml:id="br">Roberts, Briana</name> <name xml:id="sh">Hanna, Sam</name> <name xml:id="da">Adams, Deb</name> <name xml:id="lc">Clark, L.</name>  Proofreading</change>
<change when="2018"><name>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Crowdsourcing (transcribe.unl.edu)</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="program">

<pb facs="wfc.mem00014.001"/>

<div2><head>BUFFALO BILL'S OWN BOOK&#8212;WRITEN BY HIMSELF.</head> 
<p>A book of great Historical value and thrilling adventures. Written by the Last and Greatest representative of Western Heroes, Scouts and Indian Fighters. The Great Standard book of Western life, of incalculable value to all who would read the true story of the most interesting period of our Country's history. Finely illustrated and splendidly written.</p></div2>

<div2><head>STORY OF THE WILD WEST AND CAMP-FIRE CHATS,</head>

<head>By HON. W. F. CODY, (Buffalo Bill.)</head>

<figure n="drawing"><p>Wild Life on the Plains&#8212;A "Bucking Broncho." </p></figure>

<p><hi rend="italic">In all the realms of romance nothing more weird or fascinating can be found than the story of our Western Frontier.</hi></p>

<p>This wonderous tale has been told a thousand times in prose and song, yet the charm remains fresh with each recital.</p>

<ab>THE STORY OF LIBERTY ITSELF</ab>

<p>Is not more precious to patriotic hearts, for in the struggles, defeats, triumphs and examples of desperate daring which crowd the annals of Western civilization, our very souls are thrilled with </p>

<ab>ECSTACY AND PRIDE FOR THE Glorious Achievements </ab>

<p>which won and transmitted to us the heritage of so grand a nation, whose domain stretches in unbroken unity from ocean to ocean.</p> 

<figure n="drawing"><p>Buffalo Bill's First Serious Encounter with Indians.</p></figure></div2>

<div2>
<ab>While others have essayed to write the history of civilization's march across the Continent, it has been reserved for <hi rend="underline">BUFFALO BILL,</hi> </ab>
<ab>THE LAST REPRESENTATIVE OF THE <hi rend="italic">TYPICAL FRONTIERSMAN</hi> </ab>
<ab>THE HERO OF A HUNDRED BATTLES with Indians, the ideal pioneer and exemplar of
Wild Life and Exciting Adventure IN THE FAR WEST, </ab>
<ab>to give a just estimate of the truly great characters who prepared the way, by their INTREPID COURAGE AND HEROIC SACRIFICES, for peaceful occupation and stirring industry in that now doubly blessed section. </ab>

<ab>Buffalo Bill, whose name and deeds excite The Admiration of the World, While active in the discharge of duties that called forth the <hi rend="underline">CUNNING AND DARING OF AN INDIAN FIGHTER,</hi> and scout and guide for our armies operating against hordes of vengeful savages, was a careful observer of men and a student of the times, as well as of his surroundings. </ab>

<figure n="drawing"><p>HON. W. F. CODY, (BUFFALO BILL.)</p></figure>

<p><hi rend="italic">Fortune having placed him in [the] forefront of the march of Western settlement, and made him a powerful instrument for the redemption of an immense territory that for centuries was only a wide waste for roaming bands of cruel barbarians, he became specially qualified to write a history of the reclamation of the Wild West.</hi></p>

<ab>But in addition to his special qualifications, for many years Buffalo Bill</ab>

<ab>MADE A STUDY OF THE GREAT FRONTIERSMEN WHO PRECEDED HIM,</ab>

<ab>and of the conditions and circumstances that rendered their names illustrious. After a long period of patient research in history, and of social intercourse with those who could give reliable details of incidents connected with pioneer occupation of the West, he began the preparation of a book that should truthfully reflect not only the lives of those whom he chose to describe, but their ambitions, promptings, sacrifices and surroundings.</ab>
</div2>

<div2>

<figure n="drawing"><p>Photographic View of the Arena of the Wild West Show in London.</p></figure>

<p>As the work thus undertaken progressed, his plan assumed a systematic form and developed at length into a well-executed result</p>
 
<ab>IN THE STORY OF THE Wild West </ab>

<ab>a book of such really marvelous interest, historical value, and exceedingly great literary excellence that it must immediately occupy, and for centuries retain, a prominent place in public appreciation.</ab>

<figure n="drawing"><p>Maj. Ballard's Heroic Defence of his Home.</p></figure>
</div2>

<pb facs="wfc.mem00014.002"/>

<div2>
<figure n="drawing"><p>Buffalo Bill Giving Four Kings a Wild Ride in the Deadwood Coach. </p></figure>

<figure n="drawing"><p>Kit Carson Wounded while Protecting a Comrade.</p></figure>

<head>BUFFALO BILL IS THE LAST OF HIS RACE.</head>

<p>There can be no more great American Scouts and Hunters, because the conditions that produced them have passed away. The buffalo has disappeared entirely, and there are only a few miserable remnants of the once fierce and powerful tribes of red men that rode as monarchs over the hills and plains of the great West&#8212;</p>

<p>It is, therefore, peculiarly appropriate that Buffalo Bill, THE LAST REPRESENTATIVE WESTERN HERO AND SCOUT, should put in enduring form the story of his own Marvelous Achievements, and also those of</p>

<ab>ALL THE OTHER GREAT FRONTIERSMEN THAT PRECEDED HIM.</ab>

<p>By doing so he has embalmed in Imperishable History a complete description of the settlement of the American Wilderness, covering THE ENTIRE FIELD OF SOUL-STIRRING ADVENTURES WITH INDIANS AND FIERCE ANIMALS THAT ONE HUNDRED YEARS AGO HAD THEIR HAUNTS IN UNEXPLORED REGIONS OF MOUNTAIN, GLEN, DEEP FORESTS AND PRAIRIES OF AMERICA.</p>

<p><hi rend="underline">"THE STORY OF THE WILD WEST"</hi> is not, however, limited to biographical history, but is builded, so to speak, upon the lives of Boone, Crockett and Carson, because their careers correspond respectively with the three ages of Western progress, viz. : that of the </p>

<ab><hi rend="italic">Flint-Lock, Percussion-Cap</hi> AND <hi rend="italic">Repeating Rifle.</hi></ab>

<p>The flint-lock practically expired at the Mississippi banks, to be succeeded by the percussion-cap, which Crockett carried to the far South-west, where it won the independence of Texas and prepared the way for advancing hordes of indus-

<figure n="drawing"><p><persName xml:id="custer.g">Custer's</persName> Last Fight. Discovery of the Remains by the Relief Party.</p></figure>

trious settlers. Worn out in a noble service, the percussion-cap bequeathed to its successor, the repeating rifle, the duty of destroying the last obstacles to permanent and complete occupation of the great West, a mission which it partially accomplished during the life of Kit Carson, and which was completed when Buffalo Bill surrendered his commission as scout to spend his latter years upon the exciting, though peaceful, mimic stage.</p>

<p>The Story of the Period of <hi rend="italic">DANIEL BOONE'S ACHIEVEMENTS,</hi> as written by Buffalo Bill, is one of the most valuable contributions to history made since that justly renowned character passed from the stage of action. It presents Boone in a stronger light than he has heretofore occupied in Western annals, and accords him a position in history of which every true American may well feel proud. The author has delved deeply for his facts, and to acquaint himself with the interesting events of Boone's life he went among the old settlers of Kentucky and Missouri and personally sought his information from those best acquainted with the great frontiersman. By this patient investigation and inquiry,</p>
 
<ab><hi rend="italic">HUNDREDS OF INCIDENTS OF INTENSE INTEREST WERE LEARNED WHICH HAVE NEVER BEFORE BEEN PUBLISHED.</hi></ab>

<figure n="drawing"><p>Buffalo Bill's Introduction to the <persName xml:id="albert.edward">Prince</persName> and <persName xml:id="alexandra.denmark">Princess of Wales</persName>.</p></figure>

<p>The period covered by the exploits of Davy Crockett, as portrayed by Buffalo Bill, is a history of such extraordinary fascination that the reader is fairly charmed with every page, and thrilled with each adventure noted.</p>

<p>In addition to being a truthful biography of this great hero, abounding with exciting adventures and descriptions of the many battles in which Crockett participated, <hi rend="italic">The narrative is embellished with numerous laughter-provoking stories of Crockett's Celebrated Bear Hunts, and of his political speeches in barrooms and on veritable stumps in the Wilderness of Tennessee.</hi></p>

<p>Crockett was one of the most unique characters in American history, and the pen of Buffalo Bill has added a new charm to his droll wit and romantic exploits.</p>

<figure n="drawing"><p>A Desperate Fight for Life.</p></figure>


<pb facs="wfc.mem00014.003"/>

<figure n="drawing"><p>A Prairie Fortification.</p></figure>

<p>Davy Crockett's career in Congress, and the sallies of wit with which he entertained that august body of representatives, and which made him confessedly the most popular man that ever sat in the halls of the national legislature, are recorded with a new charm by the faithful but racy pen of Buffalo Bill.</p>

<p>The era of Kit Carson is less interesting only because there is less humor mixed with his serious life, but here the reader will find quite as much to excite his admiration, as the history of this wonderful man is a succession of <hi rend="italic">Marvelous Adventures and Hair-Breadth Escapes</hi> IN THE WILDERNESS OF THE SOUTH-WEST which he reclaimed by a cunning and prowess unequalled in the annals of border occupation. It was Carson who guided Fremont in his memorable journey from the Missouri to the Pacific, and it was he who fought back the savage Navajoes, marked out a route and opened communication for traders and settlers to the vast region of the South-west; WHO FOUGHT HAND-TO-HAND BATTLES WITH FIERCE BANDS OF INDIANS, and whose unexampled courage compelled the admiration of his foes, until through him the government negotiated many important treaties with the most powerful tribes of the West.</p>

<p>In these three great Eras of Border History, the narrative is not confined to Descriptions of Incidents in the Lives of the Leading Characters only, </p>

<ab>BUT IT COMPASSES THE WHOLE SUBJECT OF ADVENTURE IN THE WEST;</ab>

<p>Of the many Indian Wars, beginning with that of the Cherokee war in 1756; also of the numerous Massacres, Countles Perils, Frightful Atrocities, Marvelous Deeds, Astounding Heroism of both Men and Women, Terrible Battles, Horrible Tortures, Heroic Sacrifices, Extraordinary Achievements, Intrepid Daring, Savage Adventure, and Defiant Courage in the Face of Dreadful Calamity.</p>

<p>In this direful category of fearful incidents we perceive a display of noblest manhood and the hardiest features in the character of the indomitable and fearless pioneers, Scouts and Heroes, which excites our exultation for the victories they achieved, <hi rend="underline">AND OUR PRIDE OF DESCENT FROM SUCH AN HEROIC ANCESTRY.</hi></p>

<p>The Autobiography of BUFFALO BILL, as given in this book, will be read with Enthusiasm and intense pleasure by every patriotic American. Here will be found a complete history, written by his own hand, of this preeminently greatest of Plainsmen.</p>

<p>The record of his life begins with his birth on the frontier, and a description of the influences of his early surroundings which led him to adopt the profession of hunter and scout. He tells in crisp and choice phrasing the story of his struggles and disadvantages, of the troubles on the border of <rs xml:id="kansas.bl">bleeding Kansas</rs>, where his father fell a martyr to the cause of anti-slavery; of the mob-violence to which 

<figure n="drawing"><p>Buffalo Bill Leads a Charge upon an Indian Encampment.</p></figure>

his mother was subjected, and her hard fight against biting want and merciless proscription. From these pity-compelling circumstances of his youth, the writer leads on to pleasanter phases of his life on the plains; his services as a Cavallard Driver, Pony Express Rider, a Bull-Whacker, Adventures with the Mormons, Fights with Indians; his engagement as Scout; Trapping, Hunting, and vicissitudes that made of him a Prairie-Rover.</p>

<p>He tells, with evidence of diffidence, the true story of <hi rend="underline">HIS NUMEROUS BATTLES, DUELS, AND MARVELOUS ESCAPES,</hi> interspersing the narrative with <hi rend="underline">FLASHES OF WIT AND HUMOROUS INCIDENTS</hi> that cheer and exhilarate the reader as never has story done before. There are also descriptions of his grand hunts with notables, such as Dukes, Earls, Counts and Lords, who came from abroad to seek his services as guide, and who returned laden with game&#8212;killed by his rifle. </p>

<p>The Autobiography explains also how he came to receive the appellation of "Buffalo Bill," and the reasons which led him to adopt the stage, as well also a description of his success as a theatrical star. Proceeding from this interesting portion of his life the author tells of his conception of the <hi rend="underline">WILD WEST SHOW,</hi> its organization and extraordinary popularity in all parts of America, and lastly of his <hi rend="underline">WONDERFUL CAREER</hi> in exhibiting his show</p>

<ab>AMONG THE CROWNED HEADS OF ALL EUROPE.</ab>

<p>No American, no matter how high a position he may have held among our people, was ever received with such manifestations of <hi rend="underline">INTENSE DELIGHT AND ADMIRATION</hi> as the rulers and other distinguished personages of Europe accorded Buffalo Bill in England. The Kings of Denmark, Greece, Portugal, Italy, and Dukes of Russia, Germany and Austria came to do him homage, while the <hi rend="underline"><persName xml:id="victoria.q">QUEEN OF ENGLAND</persName>,</hi> <hi rend="underline">HIS HIGHNESS, THE PRINCE OF WALES,</hi> and that grand old man, <hi rend="underline"><persName xml:id="gladstone.w">WM. E. GLADSTONE</persName>,</hi> 

<figure n="drawing"><p>Reckless Bravery of Indian Warriors.</p></figure>

extended to him the hand of hearty congratulation and loaded him with such social favors as no other foreigner ever received. To him the success of the <rs xml:id="exhibition.am">American Exhibition</rs>, held in London in 1887, was wholly and confessedly due, and his fame rapidly extended even to the bounds of China and India, from which distant lands many distinguished persons came to see him. </p>

<p>Buffalo Bill's unexampled triumphs abroad are chronicled with becoming modesty in his Autobiography, and many valuable insights are afforded therein to the <hi rend="italic">Private and Social Life of Royalty,</hi> which have not before been made public.</p>

<p>In all his successes, which may well excite a pardonable pride, the writer never makes a display of boastfulness, but preserves throughout a modest demeanor and democratic disposition that bespeaks his Intense Love for America and the Warmth of his Affection for the Companions of other days.</p>

<p>There is everything in his book to excite the pride and admiration of his fellow-countrymen, and it must remain, for all future ages, the great Standard History of the death-struggle between the white and red races on the American continent. </p>


<pb facs="wfc.mem00014.004"/>

<p>With characteristic candor and magnanimity the Author describes the heroism of his comrades, according to them the heartiest praise, thus while giving the notable incidents in his own life, he describes the thrilling adventures of scores of Scouts, Guides, Trailers, Trappers, Hunters, Soldiers, and Famous Plainsmen who were associated with him. By a happy combination of Biography, Adventure, History, and Autobiography, the "STORY OF THE WILD WEST" is made the most captivating as well as valuable book on the fascinating subjects of which it so interestingly treats that was ever published, and it will receive a glad welcome in the home of every true and patriotic American.</p>

<figure n="drawing"><p>STORY of the WILD WEST and CAMP FIRE CHATS by Buffalo Bill</p>
<ab>CARSON</ab><ab>BOONE</ab><ab>CROCKETT</ab><ab>BUFFALO BILL</ab> 
<ab type="credit">PHILA. WOOD ENG. CO.</ab>

<p><hi rend="italic">This illustration conveys only a faint idea of the beauty and attractiveness of the real volume. Its rich bindings, with gold and colored stamps, render it the most picturesque, as it is also the most valuable and entertaining work on the subject of which it treats, that has ever been published.</hi></p>
</figure>
</div2>

<div2>
<ab>"STORY OF THE WILD WEST" surpasses all other works on similar subjects for the following reasons:</ab>

<p>If Washington or Napoleon had written the history of their own lives, what an intense and lasting interest would have clustered around every word and sentence. Their books would have remained for all ages the standards of patriotic devotion and military grandeur. In the scope of his achievements, Buffalo Bill is the Washington and Napoleon of Western Heroism combined in one grand and brilliant character. He is the last and greatest of American Hunters, Scouts and Indian Fighters, and it is, therefore, peculiarly appropriate that he should put in enduring form the history of the struggle for the possession and civilization of the American continent. His book is a necessary and exceedingly valuable termination of the story of American energy, fortitude and heroism. His pen is as vigorous as his rifle was unerring, and his book will remain forever the great standard history of pioneer life in America. </p>

<p>The demand for this great work is not confined to America alone, but it was undertaken principally upon the solicitation of distinguished Europeans, among whom was the Prince of Wales and Hon. Wm. E. Gladstone, who earnestly requested the celebrated Western Scout to write the history of the struggle with the American Indians, including his own daring and brilliant career. Under the endorsement and approval of these distinguished gentlemen, and others of equally exalted position on the continent of Europe, as well as for its own intrinsic worth and thrilling interest, the book has met with the most extraordinary popularity in England and other European countries, the demand being so great that it was published simultaneously on both continents, and it is meeting with a larger sale than any other historical work ever published in the world. </p>

<p>The completeness and accuracy of its statements are among the most valuable and interesting features of the "STORY OF THE WILD WEST." No incident of importance in the whole pioneer history of our country has been omitted. Among the thousands of other incidents none perhaps will be read with more thrilling interest than the </p>

<ab>STORY OF THE CUSTER MASSACRE.</ab>

<p>This is one of the most valuable contributions to history, and Buffalo Bill's description of the great massacre, and his careful and elaborate summing up and discussion of the causes which led to that bloody sacrifice, constitute one of the most remarkable chapters of the entire work. Being a scout at the time, engaged in government service, piloting General <persName xml:id="crook.g">Crooks</persName>' commands through the region that <persName xml:id="sitting.bull">Sitting Bull</persName> had terrorized, and his thorough familiarity with the country, as well as a complete knowledge of Indian tactics, he is the most competent of all men to write a history of the great Sioux war that led to the Massacre of Custer and his heroic followers. He has taken especial pains in preparing an authentic account of the sad incident, which he presents in the "STORY OF THE WILD WEST," in all its exciting, thrilling and harrowing details, and so faithful to facts and interesting in powerful description is the narrative, that no future historian can hope to render the story more truthful or realistic. </p>
</div2>
<div2>
<p>CONDITIONS OF PUBLICATION.&#8212;This great Historical work contains 766 large and beautiful pages, in new and clear type, illustrated with Colored Frontispiece and nearly 250 Spirited Engravings, which add immeasurably to the attractiveness and value of the book. The extraordinary demand for the work, both in America and Europe, enables us to print it in very large editions, thus saving greatly in the cost of manufacture. Availing ourselves of this saving, we have put the prices so low as to bring them within the reach of all, thus insuring permanency in the enormous sales of the book, and rendering it an exceedingly valuable work for agents to handle. </p>

<ab>PRICES AND STYLES OF BINDING:</ab>
<ab>Fine Silk Cloth, Full Side and Back Stamps in Gold and Colors  &#36;3 00<lb/>
Half Morocco, Combed Edges  3 50<lb/>
Full Morocco, Elegant and Durable, Presentation Edition  4 00</ab>

<p>A GRAND OPPORTUNITY.&#8212;We desire to employ both ladies and gentlemen as Agents to sell this great Standard Historical work in every county. No previous experience is necessary, for we will send instructions with each Outfit which, if followed, will insure success. Intelligent, working agents, devoting their time and energies to the work can depend upon a net income of &#36;5.00 to &#36;15.00 a day. If our special terms and conditions of Agencies are not enclosed, write for them, to </p>

<ab>Address House nearest to you:</ab>

<ab>HISTORICAL PUBLISHING CO.<lb/>
Cor. Sixth and Arch Sts., Philadelphia.<lb/>
225 Dearborn Street, Chicago.</ab>

</div2>

</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
