<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.scr00007.078">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main" xml:lang="en">Round and About</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>Encoding by</resp>
<name>Lily Jensen</name>
<name>Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2025</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.scr00007.078</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="a" type="main" xml:lang="en">Round and About</title>
<title level="j">Sydenham, Forest Hill, and Crystal Palace Times</title>
<title level="m">Annie Oakley: marbled paper scrapbook</title>
<date when="1887-05-28">May 28, 1887</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>McCracken Research Library, Buffalo Bill Center of the West</repository>
<idno>MS6.3681</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>



<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term>Annie Oakley</term>
<term>Buffalo Bill's Wild West in Britain</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>Wild West Shows</term>
<term>American Indians</term>
<term>Cowboys</term>
<term>Medals</term>
<term>Exhibitions</term>
<term>Shooting</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Oakley, Annie, 1860-1926</term>
<term>Omohundro, John Burwell, 1846-1880</term>
<term>Salsbury, Nathan, 1846-1902</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>London (England)</term>
<term>Crystal Palace (London, England)</term>
<term>Syndenham (London, England)</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>


</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lj">Jensen, Lily </name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article" xml:lang="en">

<pb facs="wfc.scr00007.078"/>

<head>Sydeham, Forest Hill, and
Crystal Palace Times.</head>

<head>ROUND AND ABOUT.</head>
<ab>SATURDAY, MAY 28, 1887.</ab>
<p>I have heard it said that if the Crystal Palace Company had been shrewd, Buffalo Bill and his Wild West show would have been located in those lovely grounds at Sydenham. Be it so or not, anyone who has been to the "Wild West" can safely say that Buffalo Bill himself has made a big mistake in not coming to the Crystal Palace. There is a very unfinished, rough, hovel kind of appearance about the show, and do what they can appearances go to prove that it is not the Wild West at all, but a builder's field decorated up.</p>

<p>What would have been more attractive and natural than to have seen the Indian encampment ensconced on the Lower Lakes of the Crystal Palace amid the natural verdure of the beautiful grounds? What a sight to have seen the Sioux and other tribes engaged in a sham attack, by means of canoes, on the lower lake! To have had the cave the home of Mustang Jack, and the Cow-boys located amoung the zoological specimens would have been "Wild" in itself.</p>

<p>The above is now only a vision. The Crystal Palace Company have thrown away a chance that would have made Buffalo Bill and the Crystal Palace Company greater than they are.</p>

<p>I have a little sequel to narrate as to why the Crystal Palace Company did not go in for real red Indians, or rather the Indians for the Crystal Palace. This week I took it into my head to go to the "Wild West." I visited the Indian Encampment and the whole show. My readers will remember that last week's SYDENHAM AND CRYSTAL PALACE TIMES contained some illustrations of the Wild West, and I therefore took with me a dozen copies to show the cowboys and their chiefs what Sydenham thought about them. My little boy being with me, he entered the various tents and distributed the papers, each being received with many thanks.</p>

<p>BUFFALO BILL was unfortunately away, so a copy was left for him, but Nate Salsbury and Miss Annie Oakley, the crack shot, were hightly delighted with the illustrations. The latter young lady invited me and my friends into her tent, and we then chatted for about half-an-hour. After inspecting Miss Oakley's medals and trophies, she said, "This show ought to have gone to your Crystal Palace." "Yes," I replied, "it would have been more realistic." Well, Miss Oakley said, "I offered to bring a tribe of Indians to the Palace, and give special performances of my shooting exhibition. The Palace Company could only pay a ridiculously small sum, so that I could not think of engaging. Buffalo Bill knowing this, did not trouble himself about the Crystal Palace, or we all might have been there now!"</p>

<p>I expressed my regret at this to Miss Annie Oakley, and said that the Crystal Palace Company had been brought low by bad management. I added that now there was increased activity, and things were looking more prosperous. Miss Oakley was pleased to hear this, but said it was of course too late. She then took a cabinet photograph of herself and presented it to my little boy. Cordially shaking us by the hand, she bid us adieu.</p>


</div1>
</body>

<back>
</back>
</text>
</TEI>
