<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.lgl00073">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Robert W. Powers to Isaac Cody</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<sponsor>This project is supported in part by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Geraldine W. &amp; Robert J. Dellenback Foundation.</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.lgl00073</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="m" type="main">Robert W. Powers to Isaac Cody</title>
<title level="j"></title>
<pubPlace></pubPlace>
<date when="1850">1850</date>
<biblScope type="vol"></biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue"></biblScope>
<biblScope type="pp"></biblScope>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier><repository>Microfilm, Scott County Recorder, Deeds-Land-Record 1838-1885, State Historical Society of Iowa, Des Moines</repository></msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Records</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>


</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="record">

<pb facs="wfc.lgl00073.001"/>

<fw>218</fw>



<ab>Robert W. Powers Deed Isaac Cody<lb/>
Filed for Record Jany. 1st 1850<lb/>
at 11 O'clock A. M.<lb/>

H. Price Recorder</ab>


<p>This deed made entered into this thirtieth day of July Eighteen hundred and forty-nine between Robert H. Powers of the County of Rock Island &amp; state of Illinois party of the first part and Isaac Cody party of the second part. Witnesseth That the said party of the first part in consideration of the sum of Three Hundred Dollars to them in kind paid by the party of the second part the receipt of which is hereby acknowledged a by these presents grant, bargain, sell, and convey unto the said party of the second part his heirs &amp; assigns forever the following lot of land situate &amp; lying in the of Parkhurst (now Berlin) Scott County Iowa as numbered &amp; designated on the plot of said term as Recorded in the Recorders office at Dubuque in said State as follows: "To Wit," Lot six (6) in Block six (6) together with all and singular the appurtenance thereunto belonging or in any wise appertaining. To Have and To Hold the same together with all the rights <unclear/> privileges and appurtenances to the same belonging unto the said party of the second part and to his heirs and assigns forever. The said Robert H. Powers hereby covenant that his heirs Executors &amp; administrators shall and will Warrant and Defend the title to the premises to the said party of the second part and to his heirs and assigns against the lawful claims of all persons whatsoever.</p>

<p>In Witness Whereof the said party of the first part have hereunto set his hand &amp; seal the day &amp; year first above written</p>

<ab>Executed in presence of<lb/>
E. D. Gilbert<lb/>
J. Rowe</ab>

<ab>Robert H. Powers (seal)<lb/>
State of Iowa<lb/>
County of Scott</ab>


<p>Be it Remembered that on the 30th day of July Eighteen hundred &amp;; forty-nine before me the undersigned a Justice of the peace of the County of Scott aforesaid duly commissioned and qualified residing in the town of Parkhurst came Robert H. Powers proved by the testimony of E. D. Gilbert a credible witness to be the same person whose name is subscribed to the foregoing instrument of writing as party thereto and acknowledged the same to be his act and Deed for the purposes therein mentioned</p>

<p>In Testimony Whereof I the said Justice of the peace have hereunto set my hand &amp; affixed my seal at Parkhurst the day and year aforesaid</p>


<ab>Starling Parkhurst<lb/>
Justice of the Peace</ab>


</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>
