<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?> 

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.nsp03345">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Will Surrender Today</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<sponsor>This project is supported in part by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and the Geraldine W. &amp; Robert J. Dellenback Foundation.</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.nsp03345</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author>McF</author>
<title level="a" type="main">Will Surrender Today</title>
<title level="j">Omaha World Herald</title>
<pubPlace>Omaha, NE</pubPlace>
<date when="1891-01-12">January 12, 1891</date>
<biblScope type="vol"></biblScope>
<biblScope type="issue"></biblScope>
<biblScope type="pp"></biblScope>
</bibl>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
<p></p>
</correction>
<normalization>
<p></p>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term></term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>American Indians</term> 
<term>Brul&#233; Indians</term>
<term>Indian reservation police</term>
<term>Indian scouts</term>
<term>Indians of North America</term>
<term>Nebraska. National Guard</term>
<term>Sioux Nation</term>
<term>United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Pine Ridge Agency</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Carr, E. A. (Eugene Asa), 1830-1910</term>
<term>Miles, Nelson Appleton, 1839-1925</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term>
</keywords>
</textClass>
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="da">Adams, Deb</name> <name xml:id="lc">Clark, L.</name> <name xml:id="fc"> Christianson, Frank</name> Proofreading</change>
<change when="2017"><name xml:id="sh">Hanna, S.</name> Transcription</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article">

<pb facs="wfc.nsp03345.001"/>

<head type="main">WILL SURRENDER TODAY</head>
<head type="sub">That Is the Belief Concerning the Hostiles at the Pine Ridge Indian Agency.
They Are in Camp at the Mission and Will Not Be Allowed to Come to the Agency.</head>
<head type="sub">How the Commands Are Disposed of and What Will Be Done With the Brule Indians.</head>

<p><hi rend="bold">PINE RIDGE, S. D., Jan. 11</hi>&#8212;[Special.]&#8212; A wild and startling rumor went the rounds last night, and much excitement existed in consequence of its prevalence. It was to the effect that the agency was to be attacked early this morning from all sides, and the military authorities took extraordinary precautions to guard against a surprise. Traced to its beginning, the report was found to be an offspring from the vivid imagination of some one of the many sensational war correspondents now here. The Indians did not come in today as they promised, but are still encamped at the mission, four miles north of the agency.</p>

<p>The commands of Brooke and <persName xml:id="carr.a">Carr</persName>, numbering about 1,500 men, are closely pressing them; but they have orders to avoid a fight or trouble with the Indians. A large amount of provisions was sent to the hostile camp yesterday, the Indians there really being in need of it. There are a great many alarmists at the agency, and they are predicting all kinds of trouble when the Indians arrive; but at army headquarters not a particle of trouble is anticipated. It is the intention, as soon as the Indians arrive, to separate the Brules from the Pine Ridge Sioux and as soon as practicable send them back under strong escort to their own agency, where they will be taken care of.</p>

<p>Tomorrow promises to be an exciting day here, and no doubt many sensational reports have been telegraphed telling, or rather anticipating, what will happen. The Indians, when they do come in, will not be permitted to camp at or near the agency or in close proximity to any command. A line of sentinels now encircles the agency and the military camp, and inside of that line an armed Indian is not permitted to pass, unless he is a scout or a policeman. Visitors from the hostile camp have been coming in all day. All of them declare their hearts are good and that peace not blood is their greatest present desire.</p>

<p>Buffalo Bill, who has been here for several days past, left this morning to inspect the Nebraska state troops now doing duty on the frontier. He will return tomorrow in time to hold a council with the Indians when they arrive.</p>

<p><persName xml:id="miles.n">General Miles</persName> has issued an order forbidding the discussion by traders and squawmen of matters relative to the present campaign. From these people have emanated many startling rumors, and in a great measure are they responsible for the feeling of uneasiness and alarm among the friendly Indians.</p><byline><hi rend="bold">McF.</hi></byline>


</div1>
</body>

<back></back>
</text>
</TEI>