<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.2.6.0/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.scr00007.133">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main" xml:lang="en">Both Eyes or One?</title>
<author></author>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>Encoding by</resp>
<name>Lily Jensen</name>
<name>Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2025</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace> 
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>
<idno type="module"></idno>
<idno type="project">wfc.scr00007.133</idno>
<availability>
<p></p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt><note><!-- notes  --></note></notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<author></author>
<title level="a" type="main" xml:lang="en">Both Eyes or One?</title>
<title level="j"></title>
<title level="m">Annie Oakley: marbled paper scrapbook</title>
<date when="1887">1887-1892</date>
<extent></extent>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>McCracken Research Library, Buffalo Bill Center of the West</repository>
<idno>MS6.3681</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>

</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>



<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Texts</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Newspapers</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="original" n="topic">
<term>Annie Oakley</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="keywords">
<term>Firearms</term>
<term>Shooting</term>
<term>Exhibitions</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Oakley, Annie, 1860-1926</term>
</keywords>
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>London (England)</term>
</keywords>
</textClass>


</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lkw">Weakly, Laura K.</name> Initial encoding</change>
  <change when="2025"><name xml:id="lj">Jensen, Lily </name> Initial encoding</change>

</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="article" xml:lang="en">

<pb facs="wfc.scr00007.133"/>

<p>BOTH EYES OR ONE? - The question of shooting with both eyes open or with only one eye has been occupying the columns of our English cotemporaries for a long time, and remains unsettled, although the majority of those who have written on the subject believe in shooting with both eyes open. In a recent issue of the Field, London, Mr. Charles Lancaster, the English gunmaker, writes: As no doubt most of your readers are aware, nearly all Americans shoot with guns with a great deal of bend - i. e., about 3 in. - which allows the gun to come well under the right eye, instead of using straighter stocks, with a proper amount of cast off to suit the person for whom the gun is intended, so as to allow the perfect alignment for the right eye. The original gun I built for <persName xml:id="oakley.a">Miss Oakley</persName>, as ordered for her from America, was 2 7/8 in., and little or no cast off; but after trying this gun at my private shooting ground, it was found she was shooting a great deal under her birds, and at my suggestion, to remedy this, it was restocked very much straighter - viz., 1 3/4 in., and cast off 3-16 in. This gun weighed nearly 7 1/2 lbs., and although lighter than her other guns, was found to be handicapping her for the shooting she had to do, and I therefore built her another gun weighing only 6 lb. 14 oz., with 28 in. barrels, and which was stocked 2 in., and cast off 3-16 in. With this gun Miss Oakley has succeeded in doing some very fine shooting - viz., killing twenty-two starlings out of twenty-five shot at 23 yards rise; and I feel convinced, from the way in which she has shot the very best blue rock pigeons up to 30 yards' rise, that before the lady leaves England she will make a splendid score at our leading clubs. I am now building a pair of 20-bore breech loading hammerless guns for Miss Oakley, specially designed for exhibition shooting.</p>

</div1>
</body>

<back>
</back>
</text>
</TEI>
